# Natasha Daniels

(216) 374-6629 <u>natasha.daniels15@gmail.com</u> Chicago, IL 60647

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

The drive and curiosity to learn about food; where it comes from, how it's prepared, and how it's served to guests is what has led me to a rich and varied background in the foodservice industry. Learning and working with talented Research chefs, Certified Master chefs, and Michelin-Starred chefs; becoming the youngest and first female chef on the RATIONAL USA Corporate Chef Team; and being chosen as one of 5 chefs from our Global Chef Team of over 550 to be memorialized and published in our 50<sup>th</sup> Years RATIONAL Anniversary Book, have all cultivated my passion for food and sharing that passion with others.

#### **SKILLS:**

General: Leadership, Project management, Research, Presentation skills, Resource management, Planning and scheduling, Data filing, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Adaptability, Critical thinking, Creativity

Marketing: Communication (email, newsletter, announcements), Editing (visual and written), Design (Adobe Acrobat, print design)

Technical: Microsoft Office Suite, OneNote, Outlook, Google, Salesforce

#### **Education:**

Johnson & Wales University	Providence, RI
Bachelor of Science, Culinary Nutrition	<b>Degree</b> , 2018
Concentrations: Product Development and Dietetics	
GPA: 3.55, Dean's List, Cum Laude	
Research Chefs Association Evolution of Food Waste Competition winner	2017
Advanced Standing Program	Summer, 2015

#### **Cuyahoga Community College**

Cleveland, OH Post-secondary program for dual high school credit 2014 - 2015

GPA: 3.0

**Kent State University** Kent, OH Post-secondary program for dual high school credit 2012 - 2013

GPA: 3.4

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

RATIONAL USA Chicago, IL January 2020 - Present **Corporate Chef Administrator** 

Manage the RATIONAL HQ Corporate Culinary training program including:

- RATIONAL USA HQ Culinary Experience Center management of three training kitchens
- RATIONAL Certified Chef freelancer initiative Onboarding, training, and ongoing communication and management program for 130+ freelance chefs across the country in addition to creating a website with Salesforce and internal learning management system integration
- Internal Culinary Training: Start-up and ongoing training for 120+ employees and business partners
- External Culinary Training: Creation of the RATIONAL Training App and YouTube assets and content, creation and editing of printed training materials, and cookbook design and editing of "The Art and Science of Finishing – A Guide for Banquet and Event Dining Experiences"
- Provide customer support including initial presentations, product testing and ideation, implementation of systems, and train-the-trainer programs for multi-unit operators

## Awards:

- Maximum Customer Benefit Award honorable mention 2020 for creation of "DIY Application Training" and "RATIONAL Virtual University" courses utilized for internal and external training of the new combi-oven launch
- RATIONAL "Key Ingredient" Award Winner 2020 for the 'MORE Tour' Online Campaign for the launch of the iCombi Pro & iVario Pro
- RATIONAL USA 'Chef of the Year' 2021
- Maximum Customer Benefit Award honorable mention 2022 for the elevation of the corporate culinary training program and corporate event organization at RATIONAL USA HQ

- RATIONAL "Key Ingredient" Award winner 2022 for Can-do attitude and innovation
- RATIONAL USA NAFEM Show 2023 MVP Award Chef Team
- Selected as one of 5 chefs across RATIONAL AG (Global) to be featured in the 50 Years RATIONAL Anniversary book and '5 chefs, 5 continents, 5 Cult Recipes' campaign - The book contains a 2 page spread of my life story, inspiration, and my favorite cult recipe representing The United States of America

## FREELANCE CHEF - VARIOUS LOCATIONS:

2018 - 2019

The Country Club

Chestnut Hill, MA

Executed large scale banquets for 450+ individuals alongside Certified Master Chef

Feast & Fettle

Providence, RI

 Assisted in operation of a meal prep startup including execution of cook-chill procedures for packaged meals

**RATIONAL Certified Chef** 

Providence, RI

Coordinated and conducted instructional trainings for end-users in addition to providing support to clients in the New England territory

Private Chef for the Hostetter Estate

Nantucket, MA

Managed all aspects of dining for a family of 6 adhering to all dietary restrictions and desires

**OURgrain** Co-Founder

Providence, RI January 2018 - November 2019

Sustainable Consumer Packaged Goods start-up creating and selling high-fiber, high-protein flour and baking mixes made from spent beer grains

- Managed many aspects of the business including a successful Kickstarter campaign, logistics and production, website building and social media, community engagement and relationships
- MassChallenge Silver winning business U.S. Early Stage 3-month accelerator 2018 Boston, MA
- Social Enterprise Greenhouse accelerator 2018 Providence, RI

## **Chef Services Group**

Lincoln, RI

## **Research Chef Assistant**

January 2018 - January 2019

- Assisted Senior Research Chef in the development of new restaurant concepts and the consultation of existing ones concerning menu development, costing, and new systems implementation
- Developed gold standards for various CPG products and completed competitive analysis for clients

#### **Maria Peterson Catering**

Newport, RI

# **Private Chef**

June 2017-September 2019

**May 2016 – September 2016** 

Managed all aspects of dining and event hosting for a family of 4 plus their guests adhering to all requests and dietary restrictions

Agern

Manhattan, NYC

**Internship** 

- Internship at a fine-dining restaurant focused on Nordic Cuisine as part of MeyersUSA Hospitality Group founded by Claus Meyer
- Worked under Chef Gunnar Karl Gíslason learning New Nordic Cuisine while utilizing local ingredients

Dave's Coffee

Providence, RI

**Baker** 

August 2015 - May 2016

Baked and displayed all bakery items adhering to normal, gluten-free, or vegan diets

## **Heirloom Restaurant**

Charlotte, NC

Stagiaire

**July 2015 – September 2015** 

- Staged at a Farm-to-Table restaurant where nothing was sourced outside of the state of North Carolina
- Studied Farm-to-Table techniques in preparation, cooking, and preserving
- Executed 3 and 6 course tasting menus for diners and various private events

CV Page 3

Hilton Garden Inn
Banquet Cook
Twinsburg, OH
2015

• Executed large events of up to 500 attendees in the banquet kitchen

Flying Fig
Line Cook
Cleveland, OH
2014 – 2015

- Prepared and worked all stations for dinner and brunch service including prep, garde-manger, sauté, grill, and fryer stations
- Utilized local ingredients to execute a seasonal menu

Cleveland Yacht Club
Line Cook
Rocky River, OH
2014

• Prepared and executed all menu items for banquets, on-property restaurant, and snack bar during the summer and fall

Panera Bread Twinsburg, OH
Team Member 2012 – 2014

- Assisted in new store location opening
- Managed food prep, sanitation, and cooking for all stations including cashier/bakery, hot line, prep, dishes, and dining room

## **EVENT AND CONFERENCE EXPERIENCE:**

- Volunteer experience at various events throughout the country
- Liaison between volunteers and team leads for components of conference operations including setup, breakdown, management and distribution of material, registration, parking enforcement, and operations
- Management of inventory including receiving, distributing, and preparation of ingredients
- Execute event meals for upwards of 1000+ attendees including breakfast, lunch, dinner, and late-night food

•	StarChefs International Culinary Congress – Brooklyn, NY	October 2019
•	Fete De Boucheurs, Huron, OH	October 2019
•	Chefs Collaborative Annual BBQ, Exeter, RI	2017 – 2019
•	Roots Dallas, Dallas, TX	<b>March 2019</b>
•	Roots Conference Annual Symposium – Huron, OH	2014 - 2018
•	Dallas/South Beach/Newport Food & Wine – Various locations	2015 - 2019

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCE:**

Hope's Harvest Providence, RI
Associate August 2019 – October 2019

Picked, packed, and distributed unused food from farms to local food banks and program partners

Farm Fresh RI Providence, RI

#### **Volunteer: Mobile Market Packline**

October 2019 – December 2019

• Compiled orders of local food items to be packed onto trucks and distributed to RI restaurants and foodservice operations

# **Culinary Vegetable Institute**

Huron, OH

**Freelance Chef** 

2014 - 2019

Executed and worked events including the annual ROOTS Conference, teambuilding workshops, fundraising dinners, and public events

## **CERTIFICATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS:**

ServSafe Certificate, National restaurant Association Research Chefs Association, Member

December 2018 October 2016 – Present

October 2013 - Present

American Culinary federation, Member